VINUTAN NAIK

SR TECHNOLOGY ANALYST

Framingham, MA 01701 | +1-9087263784 | vinutan.tn@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced Senior Associate with 10+ years of extensive experience at Cognizant Technology Solutions and other organizations, excelling in performance monitoring and complex problem-solving. Proven in coordination with Development and production and infrastructure support.

Hardworking enthusiastic about take on exciting new challenges. Dynamic communicator with disciplined approach.

AREA OF EXPERTISE

Performance monitoring Customer interaction

Issue resolution Complex Problem-solving

Production support Vendor Co-ordination

Problem-solving Team collaboration

TIBCO Suite of Products:

TIBCO BW5.x, BW6.x, BWCE, EMS, Admin, Hawk, TCI(Tibco cloud integration), Adapters, TCM(Tibco cloud messaging), TIBCO MDM

DevOps: ELK, Git hub/Lab, Jenkins, Gitlab, Radar, Kafka, Jfrog, , Nexus, Portainer, OpenShift container, AWS Admin, Azure, Windows Admin ,Njams.

Ticketing Tools: ServiceNow, JIRA, BMC Remedy.

CI/CD Tools: Jenkins, GITLAB. **Platforms**: Windows, UNIX, Linux.

Others: SAP PI, SAP CPI(Admin Support), Apache KAFKA Admin

User management in life science products: DeltaV, Inova MES, EMS, BMS,PI, ANMS.

WORK HISTORY

JUNE 2024-CURRENT

Sr Associate | Cognizant Technology Solutions, CTS | Framingham, United States

- Excellent understanding of project issues, ability to work independently or as a part of a team and
- Involved in **RFB**(Request for Bid) projects for Tibco infra related activities.
- Handling the meetings with Business line team for translating business requirements into functional specifications.
- Have managed the Lead role as coordinating with multiple systems as middleware point of contact.
- Involved in requirement gathering and in design phase meetings.
- Performance tuning, troubleshooting, Software installation, upgrade and post installation configuration, prepare monitoring steps, User management in TCI.
- Involved in monitoring and configuring the queues/Topics & creation/Deletion and assigning the roles in TCM,TIBCO. Deploy Manage and Maintain Cloud infrastructure on AWS and Azure.
- Implement best practices for scalability, performance and security.
- Monitor cloud systems and trouble shooting issues.
- Work with Networking, security groups and IAM roles.
- Systems maintenance and L3 Support in 24*7 model and providing weekend on call support.
- Involved in creating of TIBCO Hawk rules and EMS administration activities like creating/deleting queues, topics, user monitoring destinations and store files and compact those.
- Managed in resolving tickets as per Incident, Change, Problem management processes.
- Handling CAB meeting to get the CRQ approval and implementing by co originating with multiple teams.
- Involved and managing multi weekend activities like OS patching, NAS migration,
 Certificate Migration ,SOX etc as a part of activity.
- Involved in Building/Recreating Appspace and Appnode depending upon the requirement in TEA.
- Managing in raising a case and working with vendor(TIBCO) support for issues.
- Involved in creating & monitoring Kafka clusters and services like Broker, Zookeeper.
- Install and configure all required SAP database servers and application servers.
- Manage SAP users, authorizations, and profiles
- Requirements gathering, Analysis, Architectural design, capacity management migration plan, Fine tuning the systems for performance and maintenance.

- Install,configure and maintain windows server operating systems as a part of windows server administrator
- Monitoring server health, performance and resource utilization using task manager, performance monitor for windows server.
- Monitoring server health, performance and resource utilization for Unix/Linux server
- Manage and Maintain the Active Directory(AD) including th user accounts, groups, organizational units and group policies.
- Implement and manage AD replication and ensure it is functioning properly as a part of windows administer.
- Diagnose and resolve server related issues for both Unix/Linux & windows servers.
- Work with other IT teams to resolve issues related to network connectivity or the application performance.

JANUARY 2022-JUNE 2024

Sr Associate | Cognizant Technologies Solutions | Bangalore | India

- Translate business and technical requirements into integration implementation.
- Provide technical guidance on requirements and design elements during planning phase with project teams
- Involved in Installing and Configuring of, TIBCO suite of products like, TIBCO Active-Matrix Business Works 6.x, Business works 5.x & Tibco admin/TEA setup.
- Experience in deployment and monitoring of TIBCO projects and troubleshooting errors.
- Managing CAB meeting to get the CRQ approval and implementing by co ordinating with multiple technical teams.
- As a TIBCO admin, involved in supporting and leading the weekend activities like, NAS migration, certificate Migration, firmware upgrade, OS patching, SOX, DG migration, DR etc.
- Knowledge on configuring persistence modes, TEA and BW agents.
- Experienced in TIBCO Software installation and upgrade of TIBCO products in Linux/UNIX/Windows servers.
- Hands on experience in setup TIBCO in completely new environment (staging) and deploy the Applications.
- Experience in TIBCO EMS/JMS installing the EMS, creating Queues, Topics, User's and Roles & configuring various EMS options.
- Experience in deployment and monitoring of TIBCO projects and troubleshooting errors.
- Good Experience using Apache Kafka, integrated with Tibco and communicated with multiple systems.

 Basic knowledge on other tools like Njams, TIBCO MDM, SAP PI, Jenkins, GIT, AWS admin, Rabbit MQ, Apache Kafka, Portainer, Nexus, ELK(Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana).

OCTOBER 2016-DECEMBER 2021

CLOUD OPERATIONS SR ENGINEER ANALYST | Accenture Technology Solutions | Bangalore | India

- Monitored employee performance to keep projects on task.
- Determined equipment failure root cause and implemented solutions.
- Led cross-functional team for successful completion of multiple large-scale projects, ensuring timely delivery within budget constraints.
- Controlled project costs by approving expenditures.
- Requirements gathering, Analysis, Architectural design, capacity management migration plan, Fine tuning the systems for performance and maintenance.
- Supporting the technologies for TIBCO BW 5.X,6.X BWCE ADMIN, HAWK,TEA TIBCO BW,SAP PI/PO, SAP CPI, TIBCO MDM, Windows server admin.

NOVEMBER 2014-JUNE 2016

INFRA ENGINEER | Mphasis | Pune | India

- Designed and developed the process flows using various activities that needs transformation mapping in Business Works.
- Configure Message services JMS for creating Bridge, Topic, Queue and setter properties.
- Worked extensively on TIBCO Business Works palettes like Data format, JDBC and General
- Extensively worked in XML related technologies that include XML, XSD.
- Created various XSD, X-Path transformations.
- Used XPath extensively to map the fields as per the mapping documents
- Created EAR for the process and deployed them using the TIBCO Administrator and verified those working correctly.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering: Electronics and Communications Engineering G M Institute of Technology, Davangere, India

LANGUAGES

English Hindi

Full Professional

Full Professional

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS CLOUD PRACTIONER

TCA- TIBCO BUSINESS WORKS

TCA- TIBCO SPOTFIRE

TCA- TIBCO MESSAGING